JOHN NEAGOE

Toronto, ON L4E 5B3 | E-mail: johnnyneagoe@gmail.com | Phone: (647) 801 6102

Portfolio: https://johnnyneagoe.github.io/My-Portfolio/ | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/johnnyneagoe

GitHub: https://github.com/JohnnyNeagoe

Web Developer with extensive experience coding interactive websites and apps using industry leading techniques. Developed advanced critical thinking abilities, polished communication skills and a strong work ethic through a full-stack certification completed at UofT, prior employment experiences in accounting, and acquiring an HBBA.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, jQuery, React, GIT, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4, Media Queries, APIs, REST, Handlebars, AJAX, XML, frameworks, Terminal / Bash, front-end / back-end
- Proficiency in Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook); Microsoft Office Specialist Certification.

HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS

Star Wars RPG Game

Link: https://johnnyneagoe.github.io/StarWars-Game/

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery
- Description: Star Wars themed RPG game utilizing JavaScript & jQuery to make all calculations needed for user functionality and to listen to events such as beginning the game or choosing a character.

• Travel Itinerary Website:

Link: https://johnnyneagoe.github.io/WanderLust/

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, APIs, Client-Side Storage, Bootstrap
- Description: Travel App using google API to acquire user location and destination in order to efficiently provide valuable information in a clean and robust manor and give them the ability to choose bookings.

Social Networking App for Neighborhoods

- Languages: HTML ,CSS, JavaScript, PassportJS, Google API, MySQL, Segualize, ExpressJS, NodeJS
- Description: App designed for neighbourhoods, giving users the ability to easily interact with their fellow community members.
 Link https://hi-neighbour.herokuapp.com/dashboard

WORK EXPERIENCE

LiVante Developments Project Accountant

Toronto ON

June 2017 – Present

- Improved the efficiency of the accounting system, through the timely requirement of all necessary paperwork from other key departments and clients / vendors.
- Decreased expenditure by effectively implementing contractual obligations & negotiating additional work on a case by case basis.
- Enriched productivity of construction processes through implementing a robust purchase order system.
- Developed strong relationships with executives and other employees, allowing for swift conflict resolution, increased productivity and an overall improvement in communication.

Mattamy HomesJunior Financial Analyst

Vaughan ON March 2017 – May 2017

- Enriched the proficiency of the reporting team by assisting with the creation of monthly financial reporting packages.
- Enhanced productivity in converting to a new enterprise system planning software (JDE) through multiple account analyses, resulting in the reclassification of accounts from one system to another.
- Established a strong understanding of the company environment and an ability distinguish between different types of contracts such as Joint Venture agreements.

• Greenwin Inc. & Johnson Insurance Inc. - Summer Internships Toronto / Newmarket, ON Junior Financial Analyst - 2015 & Accounting Analyst - 2014 & Claims Assistant - 2013

- Elevated comprehension of company financial growth and stability through the analysis of revenue, operating expenses and profit on a year-over-year and quarter-to-quarter basis.
- Perfected communication between account managers, vice president and director of finance through prompt reporting & administrative task completion.
- Amplified interdepartmental productivity through the implementation of a purchase order tracking system.
- Provided top-quality customer service while developing close relationships with insurance adjusters, which allowed for efficient and prompt assistance throughout the entire work term.

EDUCATION

• Full Stack Web Development Certificate

- University of Toronto, St. George Campus

Honours Bachelor of Business Administration

September 2012 – May 2016

May 2018 – November 2018

- Wilfrid Laurier University, Waterloo Ontario
- Finance Major Economics Minor